<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Jordan Learns Code]]></title>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-10-31T13:51:53-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jordan Jesse]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dirty Checking vs. VDOM]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/31/dirty-checking-vs-vdom/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-31T14:50:12-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/31/dirty-checking-vs-vdom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What is the difference between updating the DOM using dirty checking and VDOM manipulation? Is one more efficient than the other? What the heck <em>is</em> the DOM? Let’s try to answer these questions!<!--more--></p>

<h3 id="what-is-the-dom">What is the DOM?</h3>
<p>To understand the differences between dirty checking and VDOM manipulation we first need to understand what the DOM is and isn’t.</p>

<h5 id="the-dom-is">The DOM is:</h5>
<ul>
  <li>a programming interface for HTML and XML documents</li>
  <li>an object-oriented representation of the HTML we wrote made up of nodes and objects</li>
  <li>automatically created from the HTML we wrote by the browser</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="the-dom-is-not">The DOM is not:</h5>
<ul>
  <li>the actual HTML we wrote</li>
  <li>the markup we see when we choose ‘view source’ on a page</li>
  <li>always the same as our HTML(browsers sometimes fix invalid markup behind the scenes)</li>
</ul>

<p>The DOM can be manipulated and edited using a scripting language like JavaScript including libraries and frameworks such as jQuery, Angular, and React. In fact, the DOM actually has its own API for interacting with other bits of code. Much of what is thought of as a “JavaScript thing” is actually a DOM API feature that allows us to interact with the DOM.</p>

<h3 id="dirty-checking">Dirty Checking</h3>
<p>Dirty checking is when our code checks all of the node’s data at regular intervals for changes, like a loop(because it <em>is</em> a loop). It’s an inefficient way to update DOM elements as it requires recursively traversing every single node in the DOM to see if the node’s data is “dirty”(it’s been changed). Compared to “Observable Checking”, where the individual components are responsible for listening to when changes take place in the state and communicating those changes, dirty checking is slow. A good example of this slowness would be updating a <code>li</code> in an unordered list: when dirty checking discovers the updated <code>li</code> it will actually re-render the entire unordered list; a very ineffecient operation.</p>

<h3 id="the-virtual-dom">The Virtual DOM</h3>
<p>The virtual DOM, or VDOM, is an abstraction of the DOM that is lightweight and can be updated without affecting the actual DOM. It has all of the same nodes, objects, and properties as the real DOM except without the ability to write to the screen. It’s worth noting that a new VDOM is created after every re-render of the UI. When using React a snapshot is made of the VDOM before applying any updates and this snapshot is used to compare against an updated VDOM. By comparing and contrasting the VDOM snapshot with the updated VDOM React is able to update only those elements that have been changed. Unlike the dirty checking example previously mentioned, VDOM manipulation will only update the node that’s been changed <em>without</em> having to update it’s parent element or containing list. This is what makes VDOM manipulation faster and more efficient than dirty checking.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 25 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/30/day-25-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-30T23:46:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/30/day-25-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had an idea for an app last night that I really want to build, so I’m using it as an excuse to run through making a full stack CRUD app again with Angular/.NET/SQL. It’s a web app to help unlicensed social workers track the hours required for their licensure. After hearing a few social workers frustrated with the process of tracking their hours it seemed like an app that could store the hours and return some meaningful analysis to the user would be the way forward - certainly more convenient than an Excel spreadsheet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 24 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/28/day-24-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-28T22:23:39-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/28/day-24-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m working on a new feature that involves building a custom tag in Angular that incorporates an open source project. I’ve made a personal goal of solving a new algorithm challenge on (Hacker Rank)[https://www.hackerrank.com] every day for the rest of this year. We’ll see how it goes!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 23 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/27/day-23-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-27T21:40:04-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/27/day-23-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we learned more about data structures, binary trees, and how to traverse a binary tree using recursion. I’d always perceived binary trees as some scary part of the interview process based off of the complaints of tech interviewees, however they didn’t seem that complex and traversal via recursion made really good sense.<!--more--></p>

<p>Additionally, today I learned that if you want a little green square to show up on your GitHub commit graph that your name and email, specifically the email you login to GitHub with, need to be configured in git. Good to know!</p>

<h2 id="recursion">Recursion</h2>

<h3 id="binary-tree-traversal">Binary Tree Traversal</h3>

<h5 id="preorder">Preorder</h5>
<ul>
  <li>node(contains contents, left child, and right child)</li>
  <li>traversal function uses recursion</li>
  <li>print the parents before the children</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="postorder">Postorder</h5>
<ul>
  <li>print the children before printing the parents</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="inorder">Inorder</h5>
<ul>
  <li>print the left child, print the parent, then print the right child</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 22 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/26/day-22-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-26T21:40:04-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/26/day-22-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we we got into the nuts and bolts of how to build custom tags and components in AngularJS, data binding characters to be used with custom directives, and how to handle git merge conflicts. Additionally, I <em>finally</em> figured out how to handle salting a SHA1 hashed password and validating the user login and registration, subsequently returning a cookie to the logged in user!<!--more--></p>

<h3 id="data-binding-characters">Data Binding Characters</h3>
<ul>
  <li><code>&lt;</code> one-way data binding</li>
  <li><code>=</code> two-way data binding</li>
  <li><code>@</code> access a string value passed into a directive</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 21 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/25/day-21-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-25T22:05:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/25/day-21-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was a blur. I continued to build the registration and login feature for this app with Angular and .NET. I gave my first code talk tonight; it was about what vim is and why you would want to use it. I thought it was Thursday all day and it’s actually Wednesday; it’s been one of those weeks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 20 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/24/day-20-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-24T23:27:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/24/day-20-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Holy smokes. Today I <em>finally</em> completed my two full stack components, however I’ve said that at standup for the last week it seems, so my ability to predict when something will be “done” needs work. I’m excited to start working on my assigned feature for this techie logging tool, the user registration/login, mostly because with all the news lately(Equifax) I’d like to learn more about seurity and things to be aware of.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 19 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/23/day-19-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-23T22:01:14-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/23/day-19-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spent most of my day ‘off’ yesterday building a web app that can get the user’s location data and return the local weather using the Weather Underground API and the <code>navigator.geolocation</code> API built into HTML5. I learned a lot about SSL, HTTPS, and ports 443/80 while attempting(the operative word here) to securely retrieve and transmit the user’s location. You can check out my little weather API experiment <a href="http://codepen.io/jljesse/pen/LzvoJq">here</a>. Additionally, I’m trying to be better about digging into the call stack when I’m debugging; it’s a really helpful tool.<!--more--></p>

<p>I learned a small amount about cryptography and how writing your own crypto can be dangerous. With that in mind, my goal is to implement the salting and hashing of the user’s password by stitching together instructor supplied crypto libraries with a minimum of my own code. Bonus round: today I learned that encryption != hashing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 18 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/21/day-18-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-21T22:01:14-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/21/day-18-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning was rough; I felt like I wrote more bugs than functioning code. I’m trying to encrypt the user’s password before it is sent to the server and ran into some trouble with the <code>salt</code> portion of the encryption. Nevertheless, I’m getting more confident in my ability to debug things, knowing which tools to use, and how to follow the flow of data through my application from the user’s input on the front end to the database in the back end. By the late evening, I had my second component mostly complete and felt like I was able to learn from most of this morning’s missteps.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 17 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/20/day-17-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-20T22:51:37-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/20/day-17-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started working on my second component today and it was different from the first in that it already contained a bunch of code that I had to work around, which provided some extra challenges. The main thing I learned about today was encryption and how to apply it to a user’s password; trying to handle the password so that it’s secure is tricky business however I’m really enjoying the challenge.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 16 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/19/day-16-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-19T23:23:45-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/19/day-16-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I thought I finished my full stack component yesterday, however I added some validation to the API I wrote with C#… and it broke. As a result, today I learned how to troubleshoot The Unity framework configuration, how to implement validation on the server(as opposed to client side), and how to improve my debugging by digging into the call stack more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 15 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/18/day-15-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-18T23:18:23-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/18/day-15-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished up my full stack component last night and spent today giving it some styling and then integrating it into the main project. I learned some fancy git commands like <code>git log --all --graph --pretty=oneline</code> and how do deal with merge conflicts(edit by hand with attention to detail). Reading and writing code is feeling more natural with each day. I finally installed the Vim plugin in Visual Studio so that I can start moving around my code more nimbly! I find myself marveling at how clever Vim is ever time I use it - my goal is to be a Vim wizard by the end of this year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 14 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/17/day-14-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-17T23:21:48-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/17/day-14-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spent most of today feeling overwhelmed and trying to keep my head up and press forward despite the feeling. We started building our individual components today, from the database, through the middle tier, and to the front end(using SQL, .NET, and AngularJS respectively). I struggled most of the day to understand how all of the pieces communicate with each other, however by the end of the day I felt like I had a grasp on the flow of data.<!--more--></p>

<p>I was able to write a console application that allowed me to test the API I had written in C# along with the SQL procedures. The pace is definitely moving fast at Sabio however I feel like I’m learning some non-trivial new things every single day here. I’m looking forward to going in tomorrow and building out the front end of this component with AngularJS, and then watching the data go from the client, to the Angular controller, to the Angular service, to the Api Controller, to the Api Service, to the SQL database, and back again. The internet is a series of pipes indeed!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 13 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/16/day-13-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-16T21:45:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/16/day-13-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we kicked off the class project that we’ll be working on for the next eight weeks and it looks awesome. I don’t want to give too much away yet, but it’s looking like an awesome info logging tool built with developers in mind that will be open sourced as it nears completion. We spent the morning making sure that everybody was able to clone the project to a local repo and get everything up and running, along with a high level overview of the project and what we’ll be building. Tonight we’ll start working on our respective components, building them out from the database to the view in the browser - full stack.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 12 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/14/day-12-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-14T21:42:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/14/day-12-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>No Los Angeles traffic on Saturdays! That means I was able to get an early start on coding and complete another card today! I spent most of my day sorting and filtering data; it’s amazing to me how relatively easy it is to implement some of these features with AngularJS compared to jQuery.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 11 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/13/day-11-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-13T23:46:16-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/13/day-11-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re wrapping up our crash course in AngularJS and getting ready to start working on our project on Monday. We got an overview of how the full stack fits together including the front end, middle tier, and back end. Our instructor live coded a simple full stack application from scratch in under 30 minutes! Tomorrow will be the last day we spend on Angular warmups, Sunday is for life maintenance, and come Monday we will start building features for our class project.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 10 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/12/day-10-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-12T23:19:41-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/12/day-10-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spent the majority of today learning how to build more flexible views/states in AngularJS with $ctrl and $stateParams - I was surprised by how easy URL based routing could be implemented with Angular. I feel like using jQuery it required a dozen lines of code but with Angular it’s only two. I learned how to write a service that communicates data between two controllers today, which was fun to read up on, and that estimating the amount of time it takes to complete a feature is a challenge.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 9 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/11/day-9-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-11T23:42:36-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/11/day-9-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The pace here at Sabio is frenzied. Today I learned about some new git commands, using UI-Router and $stateParams with Angular, and creating and using components. The best part of my day was getting to spend a fair amount of time helping my peers. I enjoy explaining things and I suspect part of it is because if I can’t explain something simply then it motivates me to study up on the subject.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 8 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/10/day-8-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-10T22:45:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/10/day-8-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We learned more about AnguarJS today including UI-Router, how to make route tables, and how to build a single page application. Angular is feeling more comfortable each day and I’m loving that I’m able to take a deep dive into the parts that interest me like prototypal inheritance and promises.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 7 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/09/day-7-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-09T20:32:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/09/day-7-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Week two begins! I’m finally getting my routines back online and feeling like this might be sustainable. Today we covered promises in Angular, form validation, and the concept of scope. Angular is starting to sink in and feeling like something I can write and make good use of; the more it sinks in the more stoked I am on what it can do.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
