<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ruby, | Jordan Learns Code]]></title>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/categories/ruby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-05-02T16:08:11-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jordan Jesse]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fibonacci Sequence in Ruby]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/03/16/fibonacci-sequence-in-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-16T22:38:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/03/16/fibonacci-sequence-in-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I&rsquo;m teaching myself Ruby and today was all about solving some Euler problems. Euler problems are math problems at scale, so that they&rsquo;re best done with a computer and a programming language(like Ruby). When I first looked at the problem, I had an idea of what was supposed to happen but was unsure of how to write the expression in Ruby. Being a very visual person/learner, I found it helpful to write out the first few numbers of the Fibonacci sequence with pen and paper, and then to sketch in where the variables would go and how they move as the sequence progresses. Once I was able to visualize how the variables leapfrog each other within the loop and are added together for the next number in the Fibonacci sequence, it was much more clear how I needed to write the expression in Ruby. Sometimes you just need to sketch something to see the pattern. It&rsquo;s like that art school school saying &ldquo;Practice safe design, use a concept&rdquo;. By outlining my problem and subsequent solution with pen and paper first, I was able to spend less time writing code. My Fibonacci sequence in Ruby(the solution to Euler Problem #2) looks like this:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby"># Each new term in the Fibonacci sequence is generated by adding the previous two terms. By starting with 1 and 2, the first 10 terms will be: 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21, 34, 55, 89, ... By considering the terms in the Fibonacci sequence whose values do not exceed four million, find the sum of the even-valued terms.

class Euler

    def initialize problem_number
        @numA = 1
        @numB = 0
        @fibonacci_number = 0
        @sum = 0
        puts "Let's solve Euler problem #" + problem_number.to_s + "!"
        self.fibonacci_sequence
    end

    def fibonacci_sequence
        while @fibonacci_number &lt; 4000000
            @fibonacci_number = @numA + @numB
            puts "fibonacci_number\'s current value is " + @fibonacci_number.to_s
            @numB = @numA
            @numA = @fibonacci_number
            @sum = @sum + @fibonacci_number
        end
        puts "The sum of the Fibonacci sequence thus far is " + @sum.to_s
    end

end

euler_problem_2 = Euler.new(2)
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
