<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: School | Jordan Learns Code]]></title>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/categories/school/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-11-02T09:47:00-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jordan Jesse]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 28 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/11/02/day-28-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-11-02T22:27:17-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/11/02/day-28-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a substitute instructor today, which turned out to be pretty cool because our sub specialized in a different stack(Node.js) than our own(.NET), so we got exposed to some new ways of doing things and received a brief overview of Node.js.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 27 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/11/01/day-27-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-11-01T23:46:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/11/01/day-27-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cleaning up the git branch for the markdown note editor I made yesterday so I can submit a pull request today. It looks like the next feature I’ve got to build involves importing and exporting notes as JSON and using GUID’s to keep track of notes that might contain duplicate id’s on the server.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 26 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/31/day-26-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-31T23:46:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/31/day-26-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Holy crap it rained in Los Angeles this morning! Somehow, rain in LA affects drivers like snow does in Kansas; strange. We got introduced to IndexedDB this morning which seems like a clever way of storing things locally in the user’s browser(instead of a database). This afternoon I <em>finally</em> finished up the markdown editor for notes I’ve been working on the last few days! I’m hoping to move on to a feature that utilizes <a href="https://d3js.org">D3.js</a> as I’ve got a personal project I think would really benefit from data visualization.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 25 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/30/day-25-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-30T23:46:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/30/day-25-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had an idea for an app last night that I really want to build, so I’m using it as an excuse to run through making a full stack CRUD app again with Angular/.NET/SQL. It’s a web app to help unlicensed social workers track the hours required for their licensure. After hearing a few social workers frustrated with the process of tracking their hours it seemed like an app that could store the hours and return some meaningful analysis to the user would be the way forward - certainly more convenient than an Excel spreadsheet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 24 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/28/day-24-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-28T22:23:39-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/28/day-24-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m working on a new feature that involves building a custom tag in Angular that incorporates an open source project. I’ve made a personal goal of solving a new algorithm challenge on <a href="https://www.hackerrank.com">Hacker Rank</a> every day for the rest of this year. We’ll see how it goes!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
