<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: School | Jordan Learns Code]]></title>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/categories/school/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-11-04T20:39:14-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jordan Jesse]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 30 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/11/04/day-30-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-11-04T20:29:10-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/11/04/day-30-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Saturdays in Los Angeles are amazing. Farmer’s markets, no traffic, and almost always perfect weather. I spent most of the day designing a user selectable theme feature for the open source logging tool we’re building, along with a dark themed UI. I was glad to have an opportunity to dig into CSS animations after listing to <a href="http://rachelnabors.com">Rachel Nabors</a> on the <a href="https://www.codenewbie.org/podcast/what-and-why-is-web-animation">Code Newbie</a> podcast(highly recommended). I was trying to survive traffic on the 405 when something Nabors said jumped out at me: <em>perceived</em> load time is more important than <em>actual</em> load time. I had never thought about how the user actually perceives the load time of something when I’m looking at benchmark metrics for a website; it turns out those metrics don’t tell the whole story. As a result, my plan is to incorporate some of Nabors ideas from the podcast into this open source note taking tool in the hopes that it will ease the cognitive load of the user and take some of the <em>friction</em> out of note taking.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 29 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/11/03/day-29-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-11-03T23:45:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/11/03/day-29-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was demo day for a couple cohorts that are ahead of us. I’m always amazed at the amount of features that each cohort is able to cram into their app in the short amount of time they have to work on it. It’s simultaneously inspiring and intimidating to see how high the bar is here at Sabio.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 28 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/11/02/day-28-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-11-02T22:27:17-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/11/02/day-28-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a substitute instructor today, which turned out to be pretty cool because our sub specialized in a different stack(Node.js) than our own(.NET), so we got exposed to some new ways of doing things. I started <em>and</em> finished a component today that crawls the IndexdDB and exports all of the notes it contains as JSON and vice versa(import JSON as notes in IndexedDB).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 27 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/11/01/day-27-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-11-01T23:46:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/11/01/day-27-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cleaning up the git branch for the markdown note editor I made yesterday so I can submit a pull request today. It looks like the next feature I’ve got to build involves importing and exporting notes as JSON and using GUID’s to keep track of notes that might contain duplicate id’s on the server.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 26 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/31/day-26-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-31T23:46:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/31/day-26-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Holy crap it rained in Los Angeles this morning! Somehow, rain in LA affects drivers like snow does in Kansas; strange. We got introduced to IndexedDB this morning which seems like a clever way of storing things locally in the user’s browser(instead of a database). This afternoon I <em>finally</em> finished up the markdown editor for notes I’ve been working on the last few days! I’m hoping to move on to a feature that utilizes <a href="https://d3js.org">D3.js</a> as I’ve got a personal project I think would really benefit from data visualization.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
