<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: School | Jordan Learns Code]]></title>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/categories/school/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-10-09T21:30:00-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jordan Jesse]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 7 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/09/day-seven-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-09T20:32:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/09/day-seven-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Week two begins! I’m finally getting my routines back online and feeling like this might be sustainable. Today we covered promises in Angular, form validation, and the concept of scope. Angular is starting to sink in and feeling like something I can write and make good use of; the more it sinks in the more stoked I am on what it can do.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 6 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/07/day-six-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-07T21:57:37-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/07/day-six-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Sabio bootcamp schedule includes Saturdays, so after peeling myself out of bed this morning I braced myself for 90 minutes of traffic on the 405 only to find that there was hardly any traffic at all, and before I knew it I had made the journey from the valley to Culver City in less than 30 minutes; it was an LA miracle!<!--more--></p>

<p>My class has started learning Angular and we have begun replacing all of the jQuery we used to solve our assignments with AnglarJs and it’s been fun but challenging. I ran into an issue today where I couldn’t get Angular to parse even the simplest of code(something like <code></code>) and suspect that I’m having some sort of issue with project dependancies, I just can’t figure it out. I”ve tried linking to a local file, loading Angular from a CDN, and double checking my file paths to make sure they’re accurate along with my code. I need to sleep on the problem and tackle ig with fresh eyes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 5 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/06/day-five-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-06T20:53:42-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/06/day-five-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s Friday! Woohoo! Sabio hosted a meet ‘n greet lunch this afternoon for all of the cohorts to meet each other and it was great to hear everybody’s stories and put faces with the names we’ve been hearing about. My class has spent the day learning Angular and getting ready to rewrite the app we wrote with jQuery.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 4 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/05/day-four-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-05T21:55:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/05/day-four-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning we had our first standup meeting as we’ll be working in a Agile/Scrum workflow for the duration of bootcamp. We learned about object references in JavaScript and the jQuery.data function. We received an introduction to Angular and it seems we’ll be using that to build our apps moving forward. I’m excited to start digging into Angular tomorrow.
<!--more--></p>

<p>On a more personal note, I’ve been struggling to get my routines back online with the intense new schedule; 9am to at least 7pm Monday through Saturday. I haven’t done my yoga, meditation, or workouts yet this week and it’s starting to affect my productivity and focus. I think I need to prioritize my routines a little more if I’m going to maximize my experience here at Sabio.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 3 Check In]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/04/day-three-check-in/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-04T23:12:48-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/04/day-three-check-in</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We got a crash course in Git today and have been consuming API’s for most of this week’s warmup. Time management has been challenging - I’m still adjusting to the new schedule and trying to figure out where workouts fit in with code bootcamp + sleep. Nevertheless, I’m enjoying the grind.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
