<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: General | Jordan Learns Code]]></title>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/categories/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-10-31T13:58:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jordan Jesse]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dirty Checking vs. VDOM]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/31/dirty-checking-vs-vdom/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-31T14:50:12-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/10/31/dirty-checking-vs-vdom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What is the difference between updating the DOM using dirty checking and VDOM manipulation? Is one more efficient than the other? What the heck <em>is</em> the DOM? Let’s try to answer these questions!<!--more--></p>

<h3 id="what-is-the-dom">What is the DOM?</h3>
<p>To understand the differences between dirty checking and VDOM manipulation we first need to understand what the DOM is and isn’t.</p>

<h5 id="the-dom-is">The DOM is:</h5>
<ul>
  <li>a programming interface for HTML and XML documents</li>
  <li>an object-oriented representation of the HTML we wrote made up of nodes and objects</li>
  <li>automatically created from the HTML we wrote by the browser</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="the-dom-is-not">The DOM is not:</h5>
<ul>
  <li>the actual HTML we wrote</li>
  <li>the markup we see when we choose ‘view source’ on a page</li>
  <li>always the same as our HTML(browsers sometimes fix invalid markup behind the scenes)</li>
</ul>

<p>The DOM can be manipulated and edited using a scripting language like JavaScript including libraries and frameworks such as jQuery, Angular, and React. In fact, the DOM actually has its own API for interacting with other bits of code. Much of what is thought of as a “JavaScript thing” is actually a DOM API feature that allows us to interact with the DOM.</p>

<h3 id="dirty-checking">Dirty Checking</h3>
<p>Dirty checking is when our code checks all of the node’s data at regular intervals for changes, like a loop(because it <em>is</em> a loop). It’s an inefficient way to update DOM elements as it requires recursively traversing every single node in the DOM to see if the node’s data is “dirty”(it’s been changed). Compared to “Observable Checking”, where the individual components are responsible for listening to when changes take place in the state and communicating those changes, dirty checking is slow. A good example of this slowness would be updating a <code>li</code> in an unordered list: when dirty checking discovers the updated <code>li</code> it will actually re-render the entire unordered list; a very ineffecient operation.</p>

<h3 id="the-virtual-dom">The Virtual DOM</h3>
<p>The virtual DOM, or VDOM, is an abstraction of the DOM that is lightweight and can be updated without affecting the actual DOM. It has all of the same nodes, objects, and properties as the real DOM except without the ability to write to the screen. It’s worth noting that a new VDOM is created after every re-render of the UI. When using React a snapshot is made of the VDOM before applying any updates and this snapshot is used to compare against an updated VDOM. By comparing and contrasting the VDOM snapshot with the updated VDOM React is able to update only those elements that have been changed. Unlike the dirty checking example previously mentioned, VDOM manipulation will only update the node that’s been changed <em>without</em> having to update it’s parent element or containing list. This is what makes VDOM manipulation faster and more efficient than dirty checking.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac Backup Strategy]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/09/30/mac-backup-strategy/"/>
    <updated>2017-09-30T22:18:25-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/09/30/mac-backup-strategy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you’re like me, then you probably store a lot of precious data on your digital devices: family photos, videos, music, fun projects, work projects, notes, and the like. When(it’s <em>definitely</em> when, not if) we experience a device failure/loss, the last thing we want to worry about is whether the data we’ve accumuated over the years, our digital life, is safe or not. Here is the backup strategy I use to make sure that when a computer fails it’s a minor inconvenience instead of a major headache(or heartache).
<!-- more --></p>

<h3 id="the-3-2-1-rule">The 3-2-1 Rule</h3>
<p>There is a rule for reliable digital backups called <a href="https://www.carbonite.com/en/cloud-backup/business/resources/carbonite-blog/what-is-3-2-1-backup/"><em>The 3-2-1 Rule</em></a> and it goes like this: for our data to be properly backed up it needs to exist in <em>three</em> places, on <em>two</em> seperate mediums, and with at least <em>one</em> backup offsite. So if we have a copy of our data on our laptop, an external hard drive, and in the cloud we can be pretty confident that our data is safe. Let’s dig into the tools to get this done!</p>

<h3 id="local-versioned-backups">Local Versioned Backups</h3>
<p>The first, and perhaps easiest to implement, backup we should make is a local versioned backup of our data. The <em>“local”</em> in local versioned backup means that the data exists locally, physically near us, and not offsite on some remote server or cloud service(Dropbox, iCloud, etc.). The <em>“versioned”</em> part means that our data is backed up incrementally and different versions of our data are maintained. A good use case for this would be if we have a project we’re working on and the files get corrupted, or we make a change that we’re not happy with and want to restore the project to an earlier version. With local versioned backups, we can do this!</p>

<p>One of the easiest ways to maintain local versioned backups of our data on a Mac is to use Apple’s own <a href="https://www.apple.com/in/support/timemachine/">Time Machine</a> software, which is included with every Mac. We open up <code>System Preferences</code>, select <code>Time Machine</code>, check the box labeled <code>Back Up Automatically</code>, and click on <code>Select Disk</code> to choose which disk we would like to use with Time Machine. It’s important to note that the disk we choose should <em>NOT</em> be our Mac’s startup disk - it should be a seperate disk. This is so that if our Mac were to fail or get lost our local versioned backup would remain intact, keeping our data safe. It’s worth mentioning that Time Machine only backs up our <em>data</em>(photos, videos, music, notes, etc.), <em>not</em> our applications or settings, which is where our second backup comes in.</p>

<h3 id="local-bootable-backups">Local Bootable Backups</h3>
<p>A local bootable backup is like the previous backup, except with two major differences: it backs up our <em>entire</em> hard drive including data, apps, and settings, and we can use it to boot up our computer. The <em>“bootable”</em> in local bootable backup means that we can take the drive that contains our backup, plug it into another computer, and boot from it. It is a clone of our system in its entirety. One of the shortcomings of this type of backup is that if we make a change to a project that we don’t like or a file gets messed up, those changes will get backed up to the local bootable backup as well. That is exactly why we keep a versioned backup <em>in addition to</em> a bootable backup.</p>

<p>For a bootable backup I use and highly recommend the application <a href="https://bombich.com"><em>Carbon Copy Cloner</em></a> by Bombich Software. After installing Carbon Copy Cloner, we select which disk we would like the application to use as a backup(again, one that is <em>seperate</em> from our startup disk), the schedule for our backup(I recommend daily), and click on the <code>clone</code> button.</p>

<h3 id="offsite-backups">Offsite Backups</h3>
<p>An offsite backup of our data is data that is literally <em>offsite</em> - it is located far away from our devices and backup drives. This is typically used as a worst case scenario backup, like if our house were subject to flood, fire, or theft. It would be nice to know that if we were unfortunate enough to lose everything that all of our data would be safe somewhere, and with an offsite backup this is possible.</p>

<p>For most people, one of the easiest ways to maintain an offsite backup is to use a service who’s mission is to keep our data backed up safely. Services like <a href="https://www.backblaze.com">Backblaze</a> can back up our entire computer to their servers(the cloud) and restore those files at our request.</p>

<p>For the more technically inclined, I use and recommend <a href="https://www.arqbackup.com">Arq</a> configured to back up our data to AWS Glacier servers, which have relatively low storage fees. Arq is essentially Time Machine for the cloud - it creates versioned backups of our data stored on a server of our choosing. As long as we have an internet connection our files are constantly being backed up to the cloud. However, unlike local backups, we will need to be connected to the internet to restore our files.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/02/20/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-20T19:20:20-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/02/20/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey there! My name’s Jordan and I’m on a journey to learn how to code! This blog is a personal notebook of sorts to help me keep track of the things I’m learning and the tools I’m using. <!--more-->I’ve been coding as a hobby for a while now and recently I’ve decided to pursue becoming a professional developer. My goal is to get comfortable enough with the basics so that I can attend a coding bootcamp where I can find structure, comaraderie, and a mentor - and eventually get paid to learn!</p>

<p>So why start a blog? Why not? I spend a fair amount of time solving problems related to web development, developer tools, and computer maintenance and would like to document some of these endeavors with the hope that other developers might find something useful and save some time. Additionally, I want to be better about documenting my learning progress and projects so that in the future I can look back and see where I’ve been so that I can better appreciate where I am. With that said, welcome to my blog and feel free to share any questions/comments you might have. Cheers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
