<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Career | Jordan Learns Code]]></title>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/categories/career/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-10-16T13:05:58-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jordan Jesse]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Failure and Moving Forward]]></title>
    <link href="http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/02/23/fail-forward/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-23T22:34:06-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jordanljesse.github.io/blog/2017/02/23/fail-forward</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I received my fist rejection letter and to be honest it kind of feels like a right of passage. I can only imagine how many rejection letters developers who’ve come before me have received. <!-- more -->I applied to a paid internship at a company in Kansas City and received a professional yet tactful ‘no’ regarding the position, suggesting that I practice interviewing more and reapply in the future. Admittedly, I did <em>not</em> do much in the way of preparation for the HackerRank code puzzles and they wound up hitting me in some pretty weak areas(manipulating arrays, math functions, etc). However, because I failed those code puzzles I now have a better idea of where I need to spend more of my self-study time, which is good.</p>

<p>When I first received the notice that I was rejected I <em>did</em> feel bewildered, as if perhaps I wasn’t smart enough to be a professional developer. “Maybe I just should just stick to design, making t-shirts and posters?” I thought to myself. That kind of work can be fun. But, and it’s a big <em>but</em>, it doesn’t satisfy that part of my brain that loves a good logic puzzle(especially coupled with technology!). Failure is a hard thing sometimes, but I’m realizing lately that as long as I’m able to learn <em>something</em> from the experience it’s not a waste. That, and I’m getting the impression that a <em>lot</em> of professional developers spend a <em>lot</em> of time in a state of frustration. As a result, I feel the need to get my mind organized as positively as possible and to increase my mental resilience to difficult problems. It would seem that I need to get comfortable with being uncomfortable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
